<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>osman cakir</title>
    <link>https://osmancakir.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on osman cakir</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://osmancakir.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmankerl Time Machine</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/schmankerl_time_machine_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/schmankerl_time_machine_project/</guid>
      <description>The project was created as part of the culture hackathon for open culture data, Coding da Vinci Süd 2019, and won the prize in the most technical category.
Project Description  Always the same dishes on your dining table? Are you desperately looking for some inspiration for your culinary everyday life? So not all hope is lost yet! &amp;ldquo;Schmankerl Time Machine&amp;rdquo; invites you to a culinary time travel through the traditional history of Munich-based restaurants during the past 150 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript ES7 1 : Introduction</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook1/</guid>
      <description>I started learned programming with Python and Jupyter Notebooks. The ease to share a notebook and watching cell by cell what the code does was key to me to demistify software development. I am now addicted to this approach.
Currently I am working on a research data management tool which is written in pure JS and so I want to get better at JS7 functionalities. I also wanted to have a reference sheet for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript ES7 2 : Arrays, Functions and Logic</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook2/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue where we left off.
Contents 8 - Arrays * Store Data in Arrays * Nested Arrays : Multidimensional Arrays * Access Data in Arrays with Indexes * Arrays are Mutable * Manipulating Arrays push() pop() shift() unshift() 9 - Functions * A Simple Function * Global Scopes and Functions * Local Scopes and Functions * Understanding Undefined Value Returned From A Function * Assignment with A Returned Value * Stand in Line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript ES7 3 : Objects, Loops, Advanced Operators</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook3/</guid>
      <description>The first 2 notebooks were actually the basics of javascript. The 3rd and 4th notebooks are more focused on new functionalities of ES7 and some advanced programming in JS.
Contents  11 - Build Javascript Objects [3rd Notebook] * Manipulate Complex Objects in JS 12 - Loops * while Loop * for Loop * Nested for Loop * Do While Loops 13 - Generate Random Numbers * parseInt() 14 - The Conditional (Ternary) Operator 15 - Let and Const Variable Declaration in Detail 16 - Specify a Default Value For a Function 17 - Rest Operator 18 - Spread Operator  #!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript ES7 4 : Destructuring and Constructor Functions</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/javascriptes7/javascript_es7_notebook4/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be the last notebook for our small project about learning JS and ES7 functionalities. Hope you enjoyed learning it.
#!pip install pixiedust #!pip install pixiedust_nodeimport pixiedust import pixiedust_node Pixiedust database opened successfully pixiedust_node 0.2.5 started. Cells starting &#39;%%node&#39; may contain Node.js code.  Contents  19 - Destructuring Assignment to Assign Variables from Objects * Change the order of elements in arrays with destructuring * Another use of Destructuring * Destructuring Assignment to Pass an Object as a Function&#39;s Parameters 20 - Create Literals Using Template Literals 21 - Write Concise Object Literal Declerations Using Simple Fields 22 - Write Concise Declarative Functions 23 - Using class Syntax to Define a Constructor Function 24 - Use getters and setters to Control Access to an Object 25 - Import and Export vs Require  19 - Destructuring Assignment to Assign Variables from Objects %%node var voxel = {x:3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL Basics with Art</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/postgresql_basics_with_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/postgresql_basics_with_art/</guid>
      <description>Create Table Let&amp;rsquo;s create a table called painters and save the data about the most expensive paintings in the world. Money value of an art piece is probably the most unreasonable one yet it is one of the first analysis that is demanded when a quantitative analysis on art is the aim. Money is cheap when compared to the true value of an Art. Only quality as Robert M. Pirsig defined could be the trade value for art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Kauai &#39;O&#39;o with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/cnns_vgg16_keras_simplest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/cnns_vgg16_keras_simplest/</guid>
      <description>In this notebook we are just going to look at the VGG16 model and try a simple prediction with a now unfortunately extinct Kauai &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo;o bird&amp;rsquo;s photo.
The sweet, bell-like tones of the Kauai O&amp;rsquo;o were heard for the last time nearly 20 years ago. Below through the link you can listen to its sad song.

Let&amp;rsquo;s also look at the photo I am going to use for this example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Personal Historical Revision</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/articles/historical_revision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/articles/historical_revision/</guid>
      <description>[TL;DR]
 I studied Economics in my Bachelor and M.Sc. degrees. I was planning to be in Academic in this field. I changed my mind at the Master&amp;rsquo;s degree because I didn&amp;rsquo;t like mainstream economics approach. I learned coding while I was trying to figure out what to do next in my life. I loved coding, An opportunity has risen to jump on board at digitl art history research with the new acquired skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 1 : Introduction</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_1_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_1_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Python started as a fun project by a dutch guy who got bored on a Christmas Holiday. Check out this guy. He is cool. Guido van Rossum
Anyways we are going to do some basic calculations, introducing variables and data types in this introduction tutorial.
Let&amp;rsquo;s Start I am psyched!
Calculations As you can guess basic calculation operators are : summing: &amp;lsquo; + &amp;lsquo;, subtracting: &amp;lsquo; - &amp;lsquo;, Multiplying: &amp;lsquo; * &amp;lsquo; Division: &amp;lsquo; / &amp;lsquo;, Exponentiation: &amp;lsquo; ** &amp;lsquo;, and Modulo: &amp;lsquo; % &amp;rsquo; (Which is the operation for giving you the result of the reminder of a division)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 2 : Manipulating Lists</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_2_manipulating_lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_2_manipulating_lists/</guid>
      <description>First let&amp;rsquo;s create a list called cars
cars=[&amp;#39;porsche&amp;#39;,60, &amp;#39;audi&amp;#39;,37, &amp;#39;mercedes&amp;#39;, 45, &amp;#39;bmw&amp;#39;,43, &amp;#39;vw&amp;#39;, 32] Changing Elements is easy. Call the element by it&amp;rsquo;s index and equal to something else.
cars[8]=&amp;#39;skoda&amp;#39;cars [&#39;porsche&#39;, 60, &#39;audi&#39;, 37, &#39;mercedes&#39;, 45, &#39;bmw&#39;, 43, &#39;skoda&#39;, 32]  You can change multiple entries analoguously.
cars[8:]=[&amp;#39;fiat&amp;#39;,22]cars [&#39;porsche&#39;, 60, &#39;audi&#39;, 37, &#39;mercedes&#39;, 45, &#39;bmw&#39;, 43, &#39;fiat&#39;, 22]  Adding Elements might be even easier. Just call your list and add something to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3 : Functions, Loops, Lambdas</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_3_functions_loops_lambdas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_3_functions_loops_lambdas/</guid>
      <description>Please note, this is not meant to be a comprehensive overview of Python or programming in general, but this crash course covers the basics that you need to know when you work with the data. I am planning to provide some more python learning material that focuses on more of the software development topics too. However for now here we focus on data science aspects of it.
Since I do not want to divide the topic into more sub topics any more, this notebook will be a little bit long and we will cover many stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 4 : Data Analysis with Numpy</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_4_data_analysis_with_numpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/python/python_4_data_analysis_with_numpy/</guid>
      <description>We will have 3 big sections on NumPy.
 1 - NumPy Introduction 2 - NumPy Indextion and Selection 3 - NumPy Operations  1 - NumPy Introduction Installation Instructions It is highly recommended you install Python using the Anaconda distribution to make sure all underlying dependencies (such as Linear Algebra libraries) all sync up with the use of a conda install. If you have Anaconda, install NumPy by going to your terminal or command prompt and typing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending Films with Recommender Systems</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/recommender_systems_basics_recommending_films/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/notebooks/recommender_systems_basics_recommending_films/</guid>
      <description>How do you recommend someone a film? How much information an IMDB score can reveal about a films value? In this basic project, we will focus on providing a basic recommendation system by suggesting items that are most similar to a particular item, in this case, films. Keep in mind, this is not a true robust recommendation system, to describe it more accurately,it just tells you what movies/items are most similar to your movie choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Osman Cakir</title>
      <link>https://osmancakir.io/about/osman_cakir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 11:53:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osmancakir.io/about/osman_cakir/</guid>
      <description>I try to get (and give) as much as love, laughter and also an understanding how things work and evolve. I help organizing a Turkish film festival in Munich. I like djing old vinlys from different cultures&amp;rsquo; music. My favourite activity is sitting on a bench somewhere in the city listening to the wave of thoughts in my mind quietly while enjoying my coffee. These moments then become what I write about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>